翻译 西兰花小贱  想吃锅巴  小蛮腰
翻译 x6324  吃货丁小七
校对 苏小黛  somehacker
片头特效 zzzyusa
特效&后期  8T爱冰男
总监  somehacker
纽  约  市
未来
The future.
一个荒凉的黑暗世界
A dark desolate world.
一个充满战争与痛苦的世界
A world in war, suffering, loss...
双方两败俱伤
on both sides.
变种人和敢于帮助他们的人类
Mutants and the humans who dared to help them,
共同对抗一个无法战胜的敌人
fighting an enemy we can not defeat.
我们的命运是否注定如此
Are we destined on this path?
注定像以往许多物种那样自取灭亡
Destined to destroy ourselves like so many species before us?
还是我们的进化能快到足以改变自身
Or can we evolve fast enough to change ourselves?
改变我们的命运
Change our fate?
未来当真已成定数吗
Is the future truly set?
X战警
逆   转   未   来
莫  斯  科
他们来了
They are here!
没时间了
Time's up!
哨兵
Sentinels!
太阳黑子
Sunspot.
走吧
Let's go!
闪烁
Blink!
不
No!
你们来晚了  混蛋
It's too late, assholes!
过来
Come here!
双手举起来
Get your hands up!
-趴下  -不
- Get down! - No!
不
No!
我们所剩之人寥寥无几
So few of us left.
教授
Professor.
找到他们了
We found them.
中国
教授
Professor.
-波比  -暴风女
- Bobby. - Hey, Storm.
嗨  小鬼
Hey, kid.
教授
Professor.
您来了
You made it.
只要哨兵发动袭击
Whenever the Sentinels attack,
战戟就能发现它们
Warpath spots them.
于是我把毕肖普送回过去
And I sent Bishop back
在袭击发生前警告我们
to warn us of the attack before it happens.
闪烁搜索到下一个安全点  然后...
Blink scouts the next site and...
然后在它们发现之前我们就离开了
Well then we leave before they ever know we were there.
因为我们从未出现在那里
Because we never were.
什么叫你们从未出现在那里
What do you mean you were never there?
她把毕肖普送回到几天前
She projects Bishop back in time few days
提醒其他人将会发生这次袭击
to warn the others of the coming attack.
她能让毕肖普回到过去
She sends Bishop back in time?
不  只是他的意识
No, just his consciousness,
回到了更年轻的自己身上
in to his younger-self, into his younger body.
厉害
Wow!
这也许行得通  查尔斯
This might just work, Charles.
什么行得通
What might work?
哨兵计划
The Sentinel Program
最初是由玻利瓦尔·特拉斯克博士策划的
was originally conceived by Dr. Bolivar Trask.
在70年代早期
In the early 70s
他是全球首屈一指的武器设计师
he was one of the world-leading weapons designers.
但暗地里  他开始在变种人身上进行实验
But covertly he had begun experimenting on mutants,
利用他们的天赋来辅助他的研究
using their gifts to fuel his own research.
有一个变种人发现了他的所作所为
There was one mutant who had discovered what he was doing.
一个能够变身成任何人的变种人
A mutant with the ability to transform herself into anyone.
魔形女
Mystique.
我认识的她叫瑞雯
I knew her as Raven.
我们少时相遇  并一起长大
We met when we were children, grew up together.
她就像是我的妹妹
She was like a sister to me.
我试着帮助她
I tried to help her,
却反令她与我渐行渐远
but only succeeded in driving her away.
她在全球范围内追杀特拉斯克
She hunted Trask across the world.
1973年  美国侵越战争结束后
And at the Paris Peace Accords in 1973
在签订巴黎和平协定时
after the Vietnam War,
她找到了特拉斯克
she found Trask,
并杀了他
and killed him.
那是她第一次杀人
It was the first time she killed.
但不是最后一次
Wasn't her last.
但杀死特拉斯克并没有带来她预期的结果
But killing Trask did not have the outcome she expected.
反而令政府看到了这个计划的必要性
It only persuaded the government of the need for his program.
那天  他们抓住了她
They captured her that day.
对她进行折磨和实验
Tortured her. Experimented on her.
在她的DNA中
In her DNA,
他们发现了她变形能力的秘密
they discovered the secret to her powers of transformation.
这为他们提供了关键信息
It gave them the key they needed
让他们制造出了能适应任何变种力量的武器
to create weapons that could adapt to any mutant power.
在不到50年的时间里
And in less than 50 years,
那毁灭过无数变种人的机器就问世了
the machines that have destroyed so many of our kind were created.
一切都始于1973年那一天
And it all started that day in 1973,
她首开杀戮的那天
the day she first killed,
她真正成为魔形女的那天
the day she truly became Mystique.
您想回到那时候
You wanna go back there?
如果我可以找到她
If I can get to her,
停止这场暗杀
stop the assassination,
让她远离他们的魔爪
keep her out of their hands,
那我们就能阻止哨兵的降生
then we can stop the Sentinels from ever being born.
并将这场战争扼杀在摇篮里
And end this war before it ever begins.
我可以把一个人送回几周前
I can send someone back a couple of weeks,
也许一个月前  但你们说的是几十年
maybe a month, but you're talking about going back decades.
教授  您拥有全世界最强的大脑
You have the most powerful brain the world, Professor.
但意识被拉扯到极限时就会断裂
But the mind can only stretch so far before it snaps.
这会毁掉您的  抱歉
It will rip you apart. I'm sorry.
没人能在这种旅行中存活
No one can survive that trip.
如果有人的意识即使断裂了也能恢复呢
What if someone's mind has a way of snapping back.
如果有人能在被毁掉前就迅速自愈呢
What if someone can heal as fast as they're ripped apart.
好了  散开吧
Okay, spread out.
各就各位
Take you positions.
我会在过去的我身上醒来  鬼知道会在哪
So I wake up in the my younger body god knows where,
然后呢
then what?
你要到我家去找我
You'll need to go to my house and find me.
说服我相信这一切
Convince me of all of this.
你不能直接读我的心吗
Wouldn't you just be able to read my mind?
1973年的我失去了这种能力
I didn't have my powers in 1973.
罗根  你要像我曾帮助你那样帮助我
Logan, you're going to have to do for me what I once did for you.
引导我  指引我
Lead me. Guide me.
那时的我和现在大相庭径
I was a very different man then.
你要对我有耐心
You'll have to be patient with me.
耐心可不是我的特长
Patience isn't my strongest suit.
你也会需要我
You'll need me as well.
什么
What?
魔形女离开查尔斯后就和我一起
After Mystique left Charles, she came with me,
我送她走上了一条危险的道路
and I set her on a dangerous path.
更黑暗的道路
Darker path.
此事需要我们两人
It's going to take the two of us
并肩作战  不能再分开
side by side at a time when we couldn't be further apart.
棒极了
Great.
那我要去哪儿找你
So where do I find you?
这...有点复杂
Oh...It's complicated.
一般来说  你的意识回到过去时
Basically your body will go to sleep
你的身体会进入睡眠状态
while your mind travels back in time.
你在那边时
As long as you're back there,
过去和现在将继续共存
past and present will continue to coexist.
但一旦你醒来...
But once you wake up....
你做出的任何改变都将生效并成为历史
whatever you've done will take hold and become history.
对我们其他人来说
And for the rest of us,
那将是我们唯一知晓的历史
that will be the only history that we know.
就好像过去的50年从未发生一样
That will be like, the last 50 years never happened.
这个世界  这场战争
This world. This war.
唯一会记住这件事的人
The only person who'll remember it,
只有你
is you.
好了  罗根  我需要你整理思绪
Alright Logan, I need you to clear your head
尽量保持平静
and to stay as calm as possible.
什么  什么意思
What? What do you mean?
如果你情绪变激动  我将很难稳住你
If your mind gets rocky, it will be harder for me to hold you.
你可能会陷入过去和未来之间的夹缝
You could start to slip between past and future.
如果我不得不激动呢
What if I need to get a little rocky ?
想点平和的想法吧
Think peaceful thoughts.
平和的想法
Peaceful thoughts.
你有什么好消息吗
Do you have any good news?
这个嘛
Well,
你不会变老所以当时的你长得跟现在差不多
you don't really age so you'll pretty much look the same.
你不会有太多时间留在过去
You won't have much time in the past.
哨兵会找到我们  一如既往
Sentinels will find us, they always do.
而这次我们既跑不了也逃不掉了
And this time we won't be able to run or have no escape.
这是我们最后的机会
This is our last chance.
你真认为这能行吗
You really think this will work?
我相信他
I have faith in him.
我担心的不是他  是我们
It's not him I'm worried about. It's us.
我们那时还年轻  一无所知
We were young, we didn't know any better.
我们现在知道了
We will now.
大家待会见
See you all soon.
可能会有点疼
It might sting a little.
我靠
Holy Shit!
还真成功了
It worked.
发生什么了
Hey, what's going on?
-格温  把衣服穿上  -你他妈是谁
- Gwen! Get dressed! - Who the hell are you?
听着  我不知道怎么回事
Hey, I don't know what's going on.
事情就是
What's going on is
你应该保护老大的女儿
you supposed to be guarding your boss's daughter,
而不是和她乱搞
not screwing her.
我没跟她睡
I didn't sleep with her.
-没有  -没有
- No? - No.
是  我确实跟她睡过好几次  但是
I mean, yes I slept with her many times, but...
吉米
Jimmy!
那不是我  那是原来的我
That wasn't me. That was the old me.
-这个我大概20秒前才到  -是吗
- I just got here like 20 seconds ago. - Really?
-是啊  -那你的衣服呢
- Yeah. - And what happened to your clothes?
不...这...
No...Oh...
如果我告诉你
Would you believe me
我来自未来  你会信吗
if I told you I was sent here from the future?
亲爱的  先出去吧
Get out of here, sweetheart.
我们来处理这个搞笑的
We'll take care of this comedian.
不  你不会
No, you're not.
你会把你的车钥匙和汽油钱都给我
You're gonna give me the keys of your car and some money for gas
否则你会在医院里醒来
or you're gonna wake up in a hospital.
相信我  我知道这种事会怎么收尾
Trust me, I know how these things play out.
因为你来自未来吗
Because you're from the future?
不  因为这个
No, because of these.
活见鬼了
What the hell!
该死
Damn it.
平和的想法
Peaceful thoughts.
我们在评估各种国防支出
We are reviewing all of our defense expenditures
所有的黑名册都被查看过了
and all the black books are being opened.
我们不能资助一种会对付我国公民的武器
We can't support a weapon that targets our own citizens.
就算这些变种人真如你所说
If these mutants as you described,
已经生活在我们身边
are already living among us,
那他们也是在平和地生活着
then they are living here peacefully.
十年内一起事故都没有发生过
We haven't had an incident in over 10 years.
古巴那事就不算吗
After what happened in Cuba?
那件事从来没被确认过
That was never confirmed.
我们在外有真正的敌人
We have very real enemies out there.
俄罗斯人  中国人
The Russians, the Chinese.
我们现在说的是
We're talking about
我们人口中的九牛一毛
a tenth of a tenth of a tenth of our population.
-请让我为你们念一段话  -请吧
- Allow me to read something to you. - Please.
这是我们中情局的朋友们获取的
This was acquired by our friends at the CIA.
是一部毕业论文
It's a dissertation,
由牛津大学的一位变种人所写
written by a mutant at Oxford University.
我引用他的话
And I quote:
"对于尼安德特人来说
"To Homo neanderthalensis,
"他的变种亲属  现代智人
"his mutant cousin Homo sapiens,
也就是我们
which is us,
"是一种畸变"
"was an aberration".
"变种现代智人的到来
"The arrival of the mutated human species Homo sapiens.
"导致了
"was followed by
"其进化相对缓慢的同类的即时灭绝"
"the immediate extinction of their less evolved kin".
好了
Well,
现在
now,
我们就相当于尼安德特人
we are the Neanderthals.
别以偏概全  特拉斯克博士
Speak for yourself, Dr. Trask.
当初你们把我们的军队送去越南
You know, when you send our soldiers to Vietnam
却不给他们装备能打胜仗的武器
without the weapon they needed to win the war,
那是你们低估了敌人
you underestimated your enemy.
如果你们也低估这个敌人
You do that with this enemy,
后果将不再是地球另一端的边境冲突
it won't be some border skirmish halfway around the world.
我们的街道  城市和家园都将成为战场
This time the war will be for our streets, our cities, our homes.
等你们意识到我的计划的必要性时
And by the time you see the need for my program,
一切都将来不及了
it will be too late.
而你们这辈子  会输掉两场战争
And you will have lost two wars in one life time.
对不起  特拉斯克博士
We're sorry, Dr. Trask.
你的哨兵计划
But your Sentinel Program,
是不会被采纳的
it ain't gonna fly.
西  贡
您有事吗  上校
Can I help you, Colonel?
我来给我的孩子们好好道个别
Just here to give my boys a proper send off.
抱歉长官  但我们有命令
I'm sorry, sir. But we have orders.
这是隔离区
This is a quarantined area.
让开  士兵  这是命令
Stand aside, soldier. That's an order.
起立
Attention.
休息
At ease.
这些都是什么
What is all this?
实验报告  验血报告
Lab reports, blood tests.
全部准备打包送回去
It's all getting packed up and shipped back.
送到哪里去
Where is it going?
他们也会去的地方
Same place as they are.
特拉斯克企业
Trask Industries.
特拉斯克企业  绝密
亚历山大·萨默斯  1973年1月21日
走吧  先生们
Let's go, gentlemen.
带你们离开这个鬼地方
Taking you out of this shit show.
回家吗
Shipping home?
暂时不回
Not just yet.
那些是干什么的
What are you doing with those?
它会令我们的旅途更平稳
It's gonna make the ride a little smoother.
我们要把你们转移到一个私人机构
We are transferring you to a private facility,
在那里我们可以...做几次测试
where we can...run a few more tests.
你们不是军队的人
Your men are not military.
私人机构  我们授权遣送这些人
Private outfit. We're authorized to remand these men.
这些人要回家
These troops are going home.
这个嘛  上校...
Well, Colonel...
我想这事不在你的管辖范围内
I don't believe you have jurisdiction in this matter.
我想我管得着  孩子
I'm afraid I do, son.
对不起  你是谁
I'm sorry. Who are you?
问题是  少校
The question is, Major.
小威廉·史崔克
你是谁
Who are you?
瑞雯
Raven.
那不是我的名字
That's not my name.
-我搞得定  -我知道
- I had that. - I know.
我们出去吧  快点  我们走
Let's move out. Come on, let's go.
埃里克呢
Where's Erik?
我现在单干了
I'm on my own now.
走吧  动起来
Let's go. Move it.
先别起飞
Hold that plane!
我可不想让这些孩子留在这个倒霉的国家
I don't wanna leave these boys in this godforsaken country.
你不跟我们一起走了  是吗
You're not coming with us, are you?
我的仗还没打完  敌人还在四处横行
My war is not over. The enemy is still out there.
他们去哪儿了
Where did they go?
那四个二等兵  他们去哪儿了
The four privates. Where did they go?
他们朝停机坪去了
They were heading towards the tarmac.
私宅
闲人免入
泽维尔天才少年学校
您有事吗
Can I help you?
这学校怎么了
Yeah, what happened to the School?
关闭很多年了
School has been shut for years.
您是家长吗
Are you a parent?
当然不是
Sure as I hope not.
-你哪位  -我是汉克
- Who are you? - I'm Hank.
汉克·麦考伊  现在照料这房子
Hank Maccoy, look after the house now.
你就是野兽
You are Beast?
瞧瞧你  看来是大器晚成啊
Look at you, guess you are a late bloomer.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
请回吧
I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
-教授呢  -这里没有教授
- Where is the professor? - There is no professor here.
人瘦力气倒挺大
You're pretty strong for a scrawny kid.
你确定现在体内没有个小野兽吗
Come on, you sure there is no a little Beast in here?
-好了吧  野兽  -他不在这儿
- Come on, Beast. - He is not here.
-让开  野兽  -不
- Come on, Beasty. - No!
我说了学校已经关闭  请你离开
I said, the school is closed. You need to leave.
我必须得见教授
Not until I see the professor.
这儿没有教授  听不懂吗
There is no professor here. I told you that.
孩子  我俩以后会成为好兄弟
Look, kid. You and I are gonna be good friends.
只是你现在还不知道
You just don't know it yet.
教授
Professor!
汉克  发生什么事了
Hank, what's going on here?
-教授  -请别这么称呼我
-Professor. -Please do not call me that.
你认识这人吗
What, you know this guy?
有点眼熟
Yeah, he looks slightly familiar
快从吊灯上下来  汉克
Get off the bloody chandelier, Hank.
你能走路
You can walk.
真有洞察力
You're a perceptive one.
但埃里克说...
I thought Erik...
这么有洞察力
which makes it slightly pathetic
居然没看见大门口的告示
that you managed to miss our sign on the way in.
这里是私人宅邸  朋友
This is private property my friend,
我得让他送你离开
I'm gonna have to ask him to ask you to leave.
抱歉  恕难从命
Well, I'm afraid I can't do that because...
有人派我来找你的
Because I was sent here for you.
不管谁派你来的  告诉他我没空
Well, tell whoever it was that sent you that I'm busy.
这可不好办
This gonna be a little tricky,
因为派我来的人  就是你自己
because the person who sent me was you.
-什么  -50年后的你
- What? - About 50 years from now.
50年后  你是说未来的50年后吗
50 years from now, like in the future 50 years from now.
-未来的我把你派来的  -没错
- I sent you from the future. - Yeah.
滚你妈的
Piss off.
如果你的超能力还在  就会明白这是实话
If you had your powers, you'd know I was telling the truth.
你怎么知道我失去了我的...
How do you know I don't have my...
你究竟是谁
Who are you?
已经告诉你了
I told you.
中情局的人吗
You are CIA?
不是
No.
你在监视我
You were watching me.
我了解你  查尔斯
I know you, Charles.
你我是相识多年的好友
We've been friends for years.
我知道你9岁时发现了自己有超能力
I know your powers came when you were 9.
一开始你以为自己疯了
I know you thought, you were going crazy
脑子里声音响个不停
when it started, all the voices in your head.
直到12岁那年
and it wasn't until you were 12 that
你才明白  那些原来是别人脑子里的想法
you realized all the voices were in everyone else's head.
还要我继续说吗
Do you want me to go on?
这些我从没和人提过
I never told anyone that.
暂时没有  但你以后会说的
Not yet no, but, you will.
好吧  你引起我的兴趣了  找我什么事
Alright you've picked my interest, what do you want?
我们得阻止瑞雯
We have to stop Raven.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
看来我该醒醒了
Think I'd like to wake up now.
她跟这事有什么关系
What does she have to do with this?
你说他们得到了瑞雯的能力  然后呢
So, you're saying that they took Raven's power and what?
将它制成了武器吗
They weaponized it?
没错
Yep.
她很特别
She is unique.
的确
Yes, she is.
起初  哨兵只以变种人为目标
In the beginning, the sentinels were just targeting mutants.
后来  他们开始识别非变种人的基因
Then they began to identify the genetics in non-mutants.
会有变种后代的普通人也被盯上了
Who would eventually have mutant children or grandchildren.
很多普通人试图支援我们  却惨遭屠杀
Many of the humans tried to help us, it was a slaughter.
只剩下最邪恶的人类掌权
Leaving only the worst of humanity in charge.
之后情况愈发糟糕
But then it went a lot worse.
可怕得无法想象
I've never seen anything like this.
一切皆由她而起
And it all starts with her.
就算是...
Let's just say that for the sake of,
就算我相信你  也想帮你
the sake that I choose to believe you, that I choose to help you.
可瑞雯不会听我的
Raven won't listen to me.
她的心和灵魂  都属于另一个人了
No, her heart and soul belongs to someone else now.
我知道
I know.
所以我们还需要万磁王
That's why we gonna need Magneto, too.
埃里克吗
Erik?
你知道他被关在哪吧
You do know where he is?
知道
Yeah.
他是咎由自取
He's where he belongs.
你就这么一走了之吗
So that's it, you're just gonna walk out?
一点不错  果然有洞察力
Oh, top marks, like I said, you are perceptive.
我认识的教授  对那些迷途的孩子
The professor I know would never turn his back
绝不会一走了之
on someone who lost their path.
对他爱的人  更加不会
Especially someone he loved.
我好像想起来你是谁了
You know, I think I do remember you now.
很久以前  我们曾向你求助
Yeah, we came to you a long time ago seeking your help.
我把当时你说的话  再还给你
And I'm gonna say to you what you said to us then,
滚你妈的
Fuck off!
你个孬种给我听好  我经历过很多
Listen to me you little shit, I've come a long way,
也目睹过无数人死去
and I watched a lot of people die,
善良的人们  亲朋好友
good people, friends.
如果你要自艾自怜  毫无作为
if you're gonna wallow in self pity and do nothing,
那你也会经历同样的悲剧  明白吗
Then you're gonna watch the same thing, you understand?
反正人迟早都要死的
We all have to die some time.
我告诉你了  这里没有教授
I told you, there is no professor here.
到底发生了什么事
What the hell happened to him?
他失去了一切
He lost everything.
埃里克  瑞雯  他的双腿
Erik, Raven, his legs.
他修建了学校  实验室  这整个地方
He built the school, the labs, this whole place.
怎知一个学期之后
And just after the first semester,
越战形势越来越糟糕
the war in Vietnam got worse.
许多教师学生都被强拉充军
Many of the teachers and students were drafted.
这击垮了他
It broke him.
他把自己封闭了起来
He retreated into himself...
我想帮他做点什么
I wanted to help do something so..
于是我研究出了治疗他脊椎的血清剂
So I designed a serum to treat his spine,
源自我控制自己异变的配方
Derived from the same formula that helps me control my mutation.
我自己的剂量  刚好能制衡异变
I take just enough to keep myself balanced but,
但他用的太多了
he takes too much.
我试过给他减量  但他无法忍受那痛苦
I tried easing him back but he just couldn't bear the pain
脑子里的那些声音
The voices...
用药之后  他又能走路了
The treatment gives him his legs but,
但还是不够
it's not enough.
他
He's...
他真的失去太多了
He's just lost too much.
你不怕我吗
You're not scare to me?
我一直相信世上不可能只有我一个
I always believed I couldn't be the only one in the world.
我叫查尔斯·泽维尔
Charles Xavier.
我叫瑞雯
Raven.
饿了吗  你一个人吗
You're hungry and alone?
想吃什么随便拿
Take whatever you want.
我们有很多食物  你用不着偷
We got lots of food, you don't have to steal.
你以后再也不用偷了
In fact, you never have to steal again.
我保证
And that's a promise.
我会帮你找到她
I'll help you get her.
不是因为那些关于未来的鬼话  是为了她
Not for any of your future shots but for her.
很好
Fair enough.
话先说在前头  你不了解埃里克
I'm telling you this, you do not know Erik.
那人是个魔鬼  杀人犯
The man is a monster. A murderer.
你觉得你能劝瑞雯改变主意
You think you can convince Raven to change?
把她劝回家
To come home?
很好
Splendid.
但你凭什么觉得你能改变他
But what makes you think you can change him?
因为是你和埃里克一起派我回来的
Because you and Erik sent me here back together.
关押他的房间
The room they're holding him in was built
建于二战钢铁匮乏时期
during the 2nd World War when there was a shortage of steel.
地基是纯水泥沙石  不掺杂一点金属
So the foundation is pure concrete and sand, no metal.
他被关在地下一百层
And he's being held a 100 floors beneath
整栋大楼看守密不透风
the most heavily guarded building on the planet.
他为什么被关
Why is he in there?
他没告诉你吗
What, he forgot to mention?
暗杀肯尼迪
JFK.
是他杀的
He killed him?
不然怎么解释
What else would explain the
子弹神奇地在半空变轨了呢
bullet miraculously curving through the air.
埃里克可是玩枪老手
Erik's always had a way with guns.
你确定还要把他弄出来吗
Are you sure you want to carry on with this?
你提的计划  不是我
This is your plan, not mine.
可没人能帮我们进去  还得出来
We don't have any resources to get us in, or out.
只有我和汉克
It's just me and Hank.
我认识个人
I know a guy.
现在应该还是少年  住在华盛顿特区附近
Yeah, he'd be a young man now grew up outside of DC
他能上天入地
He could get into anywhere,
只是不知道要怎么找到他
just don't know how the hell we're gonna find him.
历史重演啊
History provided the question.
可以在电话簿上找
We have a phone book.
您不是准备出行吗  先生
I thought you'd be getting ready for your trip, sir.
来拿些文件
I just came to grab couple of files.
新围巾吗
Is that a new scarf?
挺好看的
It's nice.
谢谢
Thank you.
尸检报告
特拉斯克博士
Dr. Trask.
稍等
One second.
巴黎会议新增了一些出席人员
We added some names to the Paris meeting
谢谢
Thank you.
您不舒服吗  先生
Is there something wrong, sir?
没有
No.
没事
It's nothing.
请把日程表打一份给我好吗
Would you mind typing up my itinerary.
我不想有任何遗漏
I don't wanna miss anything.
就这  就这  停车
Here, here, here. Just stop here.
知道了  知道了
Alright, alright.
下次我开车  别太得意
Next time I'll drive. Don't get use to it.
马克西莫夫
他又犯什么事了
What has he done now?
拿了多少  我直接写支票
I'll just write you a check for whatever he took.
我们只想跟他谈谈
We just need talk to him.
皮特  警察先生又来了
Peter, the cops are here, again.
不是我干的
Guess what, I didn't do anything
我一天都待在家里
I've been here all day.
放松  皮特  我们不是警察
Just relax Peter, we are not cops.
当然不是
Of course you're not cops,
是警察就不会租车来了
if you were cops you wouldn't drive a rental car
你怎么知道我们是租的车
How'd you know we got a rental car?
我查了你们的登记记录
I checked your registration
就你们走进来的时候
when you were walking through the door,
反正你们还在走
I also had some time to kill
我就顺便看了租车协议
so I went through your rental agreements,
发现你们是外地人
saw you were from out of town.
联邦调查局的吗
Are you FBI?
看来不是  这个天才少年学校是什么地方
No, you're not cops, hey what's up with this gifted youngster's place
一张旧名片而已
That's an old card.
他真厉害
He is fascinating,
他是个混球
He is a pain in the ass.
是瞬间移动吗
What, a teleporter?
不  就是速度快
No, He's just fast.
我认识他的时候  他可没这么年轻
When I know him he wasn't so young.
年轻  是你们老吧
Young? You're just old.
你不怕向人展示你的超能力吗
So you're not afraid to show your powers?
超能力  什么东西  说什么呢
Power? What power? What you talking about?
你看到什么不寻常的事了吗
You see some strange here?
说出去也没人会相信
Nothing anybody would believe if you told them.
你们是什么人  找我干什么
So who are you? What do you want?
我们需要你帮个忙  皮特
We need your help, Peter.
什么忙
What?
潜入一座严防死守的大楼
Break into a highly secured facility
救个人出来
and get someone out.
越狱吗
Prison break?
那可是违法的
That's illegal, you know.
被抓住了才算违法
Well, only if you get caught.
有啥好处
What's there in for me?
你个偷盗狂  我们要潜入的是五角大楼
You, the kleptomaniac, get to break into the Pentagon.
凭什么相信你们
How do I know I can trust you?
因为我们是一类人
Because we are just like you.
给他瞧瞧
Show him.
挺酷的  就是有点恶心
It's cool, just disgusting.
国防部
五角大楼建于1943年
Built in 1943,
是世界最大的办公楼
the Pentagon is the world largest office building.
本部雇军两万五千人
Housing more than 25000 military employees,
占地超过六百万平方英尺
stretched over 6 million square feet.
厕所在哪  我要尿尿
Where is the bathroom? I need to pee.
各位非常幸运  我们有...
Well, lucky for you, you have...
谢谢
Thank you.
由此往前
不得使用任何金属
监控都变成电视节目了  怎么回事
Yeah, we're getting broadcast signal down here.What's going on?
该死  快叫维修部的人来
Damn it! Call the maintenance, get them down here.
当心玻璃
...日本帝国主义
....from a Japanese empire.
战火持续了一个月
This month long battle
二战中非常残酷的几场交战便在其中
included some of the fearsome fighting during World War II.
3秒后门会打开
In 3 seconds those doors are going to open,
20个守卫已经准备好射杀我们
and 20 guards will be here to shoot us.
我知道  正等着呢
I know, that's what I'm waiting for.
你干什么
What are you doing?
护好你的脖子  防止颈椎扭伤
I'm holding your neck so you won't get whip-lash
什么
What?
颈椎  扭伤
Whip...la..sh
不许动
Don't move.
你很厉害  过会就好了
You're good. It'll pass.
我跑起来就这样
It happens when I run.
你肯定犯了很严重的事
Must have done something pretty serious.
你到底做了什么啊  哥们儿
What're you do, man? What you do.
做了什么坏事  被关到这鬼地方
What're you do? Why would they have you in there.
刺杀总统
For killing the president.
我的罪过就是为我们的同胞而战
Anything I'm guilty of is fighting for people like us.
你会空手道吗
You take Karate? You know Karate, man?
我不懂空手道
I don't know Karate.
但我知道疯子
But I know crazy.
各位男女老少  现在是红色警戒
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls, this is a code red situation.
我们得疏散整个楼层
We are evacuating the entire floor so that we,
这样我和同事才能截住犯人
my associate and I can secure the prisoner.
你们是什么人
Who are you?
我们是消防  检疫  防爆特别行动...
We are special operations CB, FE, CIED...
好吧  可能你们刚才没听见我说
Look, perhaps you didn't hear me what first I spoke.
但你们必须明白
But it's imperative
现在这里已经绝对封锁了
that you understand we're in complete lock down situation.
我们得去三楼...
We have to get into the 3rd floor...
哦  抱歉  你说完了吗
Oh, I'm sorry, were you finished?
他们说你可以控制金属
They told me you can control the metal.
"他们"
"They"?
我妈妈上过一个能控制金属的人
You know my mom once knew a guy who could do that.
抱歉  我这人不太喜欢动粗
Sorry, I'm just not very good with violence.
查尔斯
Charles.
我也很高兴见到你  老朋友
Good to see you too, old friend.
-你又能走了  -可不是你的功劳
- And walking? - No thanks to you.
我怎么也没想到你会来
You're the last person in the world I expected to see today.
相信我  要不是逼不得已我也不会来
Believe me, I wouldn't be here if I didn't have to.
我救你出去  你就得听我的
If we get you out of here, we do it my way.
不许杀人
No killing.
没有头盔
No helmet.
我就算想违抗你也做不到啊
I couldn't disobey you even if I want to.
我不会再进入你脑子里了
I'm never getting inside of that head again.
我要你答应我  埃里克
I need your word, Erik.
不许动
No body move!
站住  不许动
Hold it, right there!
-查尔斯  -不许动
- Charles. - Don't move!
举起手来  否则我们就开枪了
Hands up or we'll shoot!
-定住他们  查尔斯  -我不行
- Freeze them, Charles. - I can't.
举起手来
Hands up!
不
No!
如果我能把时间留住
If I could save time in a bottle
我首先要做的
The first thing that I like to do
就是留住每一天
is to save every day 'til eternity passes away
好与你一起分享
Just to spend them with you
如果今天不会消逝
If I could make days last forever
如果我能心想事成
If words could make wishes come true
我会珍藏每一天
I'd save every day like a treasure and then
好与你一起分享
Again, I would spend them with you
可是做自己喜欢的事
But there never seems to be enough time
时间永远都不够用
To do the things you want to do once you find them
我在这世上活了好久
I've looked around enough to know
只想与你分享时光
That you're the one I want to go through time with
谢了  小子
Thanks, kid.
皮特  这次真的非常感谢你
Peter, thank you very very much.
多保重
You take care.
我在驾驶舱看到了你们的飞行计划
Yeah, I saw your flight plan in the cockpit,
你们去巴黎干嘛
why you going to Paris?
和平协定将在巴黎签署
要是金属爪子看你还怎么玩
Imagine if they were metal.
帮我个忙  把车还回去
Do me a favor and return it for me
-好  -皮特...
- Okay - Peter...
慢点开
Take it slowly.
他们怎么找上你的
Where did they dig you up?
说来你可能不信  不过
You're gonna find this hard to believe, but ahh...
是你让我来的
You sent me.
你和查尔斯
You and Charles,
未来的你们
from the future.
你怎么失去能力的
How did you lose them?
治疗脊柱的药物限制了我的DNA
The treatment for my spine fixed my DNA.
你牺牲自己的能力就为了能走路
You sacrificed your powers so you could walk?
我牺牲自己的能力是为了...
I sacrificed my powers so that I could sl...
你又知道什么
What do you know about it?
我也失去了很多东西
I've lost my fair share.
你就别委屈了  埃里克
Hah. Dry your eyes, Erik.
这无法为你所做的一切开脱
It doesn't justify what you've done.
你根本不知道我做了什么
You've no idea what I have done.
我知道你夺走了我最珍贵的东西
I know that you took the things that mean most to me.
那你当初就该更努力地保护它们
Well, maybe you should have fought harder for them.
你想打架吗  埃里克  那我们就打一架
Do you want to fight, Erik? I'll give you a fight!
-让他来  -你抛弃了我
- Let him come. - You abandoned me!
你夺走了她  然后抛弃了我
You took her away and you abandoned me!
天使
Angel.
阿撒佐
Azazel.
艾玛
Emma.
海妖
Banshee.
这些变种兄弟姐妹都死了
Mutant brothers and sisters all dead!
还有无数其他同胞
Countless others...
...被抓去做实验  被屠杀
...experimented on, butchered.
埃里克
Erik.
那时候你在哪儿  查尔斯
Where were you, Charles?
我们本该保护他们免受残害
We were supposed to protect them!
当你的兄弟姐妹需要你时  你在哪儿
Where were you your own people needed you?
你藏起来了
Hiding!
你和汉克  自欺欺人不敢面对真实的自己
You and Hank, pretending you were something you're not...
埃里克
Erik.
是你抛弃了大家
You abandoned us all.
原来你一直都这么混蛋
So you were always an asshole.
我以为我们在未来是好兄弟
I take it we're best buddies in the future.
我花了很多年想干掉你  兄弟
I spent a lot of years trying to bring you down, bub.
结果怎样
How is that work out for you?
你和我一样
You're like me.
你也是个幸存者
You're a survivor.
把这儿收拾一下行吗
You wanna pick all that shit up?
巴   黎
将军  慢点喝吧
General, maybe you should slow down,
明天可是个大日子
we have a big day tomorrow.
我们是来庆祝的  上尉
We're celebrating, Captain.
胜仗可不是天天有的
It's not every day you win a war,
更何况是战胜了美国鬼子
let alone against the American devils.
我还要再来一瓶
I'm getting another bottle.
抱歉
Excuse me.
不  是我自己不小心
I'm pretty sure it was my fault.
-你会越南语  -我是个翻译
- You speak Vietnamese. - I'm an interpreter.
我会好几种语言
I speak many tongues.
我再请你喝一杯
Let me buy you another drink...
除非你还有其他男伴
unless you're here with someone.
我一个人
I'm alone.
你要参加明天的峰会吗
You're going to the summit tomorrow?
小美人对政治感兴趣
The pretty girl interested in politics...
果然不能光看外表啊
Looks can be deceiving.
也许是哦
Maybe.
给我看看  宝贝
Show me more, baby.
衣服  脱了
Clothes...off.
怎么了  宝贝
What's the matter, baby?
没想到我这么美吗
You don't think I look pretty like this?
来一盘吗  好久没下了
Fancy a game? It's been a while.
我没心情下棋
I'm not in the mood for games exactly.
十年都没好好喝一口了
Haven't had a real sip in 10 years.
总统不是我杀的
I didn't kill the president.
子弹拐弯了  埃里克
The bullet curved, Erik.
那是因为我想救他
Because I was trying to save him.
还没救成我就被拿下了
They took me out before I could.
-你为什么要救他  -因为他是我们的一员
- Why would you trying to save him? - Because he was one of us.
你一定觉得我蠢透了
You must think me so foolish.
你总说他们会找上我们
You've always said they would come after us.
我从没想过他们会利用瑞雯的DNA
I never imagined they would use Raven's DNA to do it.
你最后一次见她是什么时候
When did you last see her?
我动身去达拉斯的那天
The day I left to Dallas.
她怎么样
And how was she?
坚强
Strong.
有冲劲
Driven.
-忠诚  -我是问
- Loyal. - How...
她过得怎么样
How was she?
她...
She was...
我能理解她对你为何如此重要
I could see why she meant so much to you.
你该为她感到自豪  查尔斯
You should be proud of her, Charles.
-她是在为我们的事业而战  -你的事业
- She is out there fighting for our cause. - Your cause.
我养大的那个女孩不会杀人
The girl I raised, she was not capable of killing.
你没养她  你只是和她一起长大
You didn't raise her, you grew up with her.
她不能永远做个小女孩  所以她离开了你
She couldn't stay a little girl forever that's why she left.
她离开我是因为你干扰了她的思想
She left because you got inside her head.
我可没这个能力
That's not my power.
那是她的选择
She made a choice.
但我们现在知道那选择会有什么结局了
But now we know where that choice leads, don't we?
她会去刺杀特拉斯克  他们会抓住她
She's going to murder Trask, they're going to capture her,
然后我们会被赶尽杀绝
and then they're going to wipe us out.
如果我们先找到她就不会
Not if we get to her first.
如果我们明天能扭转这一切就不会
Not if we change history tomorrow.
对不起  查尔斯
I'm sorry, Charles.
为所有这一切  真的对不起
For what happened, I truly am.
我也有一阵子没玩了
It's been a while since I played.
我会让着你的
I'll go easy on you.
能让比赛公平点
Might finally get a fair fight.
你先下
You make the first move.
世界各国的外交官员今天齐聚于此
The diplomats from all around the world arriving here today at the
皇家酒店
hotel Royale.
这是具有历史意义的一天
It's a historic day as the official ending of
美国对越南的军事干预将正式结束
the united states fierce involvement in Vietnam.
现在到达的是越南外交部长
There's the south Vietnamese foreign minister
及随行官员
with other south Vietnamese dignitaries.
峰会还有一个小时才开始
The summit doesn't begin for another hour.
我们为您的贵客们在楼上准备了一个房间
The hotel has arranged a private room upstairs for your special guests.
时间足够了
That'll be plenty of time.
大家好  各位下午好
Good afternoon, everyone, hello.
感谢各位出席
Thank you for coming.
首先祝贺各位取得胜利
Congratulations on winning this war.
我知道各位都急着下楼
Now I know you all have
握手合影  应付场面
hands to shake and photos to take downstairs,
所以我就长话短说了
so I will get right to the point.
现在我们有一个新敌人
There is a new enemy out there.
一个用武器无法阻止的敌人
An enemy that will render your arsenals useless,
一个能令国防瘫痪的敌人
your armies powerless and your nations defenseless.
你们需要一种新武器来赢得这场战争
You'll need a new weapon for this war.
我将其命名为"哨兵"
I call them "Sentinels".
取自古时的城堡卫兵
Named after the ancient guardians that stood at the gates of the citadel,
飞行能力相当于一架鹞式战斗机
they have the aeronautic capabilities of a Harrier Jet.
配备的枪械
Armed with guns that can fire off
每分钟可发射2000轮热电陶瓷子弹
more than 2000 rounds per minute with thermo-ceramic ammunition.
但若有足够的尺寸  威力及速度
But size, power, speed,
洛克希德或波音的飞机也能做到这点
you could find that at Lockheed or Boeing.
不  "哨兵"的真正特别之处在于
No! What makes the sentinels so special
它可以自动搜索到变种人的X基因
is the ability to target the mutant X gene.
它的基因导向系统
The genetic guidance system
可以搜寻到半英里外的目标
that can lock onto a mark half a mile away.
并且只有确认了目标才会触发
And won't trigger unless it has identified the target.
有了它  就可以避免连带的人员伤亡
With this weapon there'll be no human collateral damage.
如果我现在打开  它并不会被激活
If I turn it on, the system couldn't even activate in here.
除非...
Unless...
这里有变种人
there's a mutant.
这一定是搞错了
There has to be some kind of mistake.
我的机器从不出错
My machines don't make mistakes.
你是什么
What are you?
我保证
I assure you
我...
I...
不  别开枪
No, don't shoot him.
我保证
I assure you.
我不知道你在说什么
I do not know what you're talking about.
瑞雯
Raven!
Raven.
瑞雯
Raven!
Raven.
查尔斯
Charles.
我们来找你了  我和埃里克
We've come for you. Erik and I.
一起
Together.
我没想到还能再见到你
I never thought I could see you again.
我曾经许下承诺要保护你
I made you a promise long time ago that I would protect you.
我没做到  我知道...
I didn't. And I know...
金刚狼
Wolverine!
我会保护你的
I'm going to keep you safe.
我不会让他们把你带走的
I'm going to keep you out of their hands.
埃里克
Erik.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
扭转我们的未来
Securing our future.
别怪我  魔形女
Forgive me, Mystique.
只要你活着我们就不会安全
As long as you're out there we'll never be safe.
埃里克
Erik.
控制他  查尔斯  让他停下
Use your power, Charles. Stop him.
他做不到了
He can't.
他在挣脱  他的意识在波动
He is slipping. He is slipping back.
他快挣脱我了
I'm losing him.
史崔克
Stryker!
总有一天我们会完成这一切  金刚狼
So we will finish what we started Wolverine, oneday.
凯蒂
Kitty!
控制住他
Restrain him.
埃里克
Erik!
我在哪儿
Where am I?
我怎么会在这儿
How the hell did I get here?
什么  你来找的我们
What? You came to us.
-你是谁  -查尔斯
- Who are you? - Charles.
查尔斯·泽维尔
Charles Xavier.
-我不认识你  -啊
- I do not know you. - Ahh?
那是啥
What the hell is that?
我来处理这个
Wow, I can deal with this.
快走  去找埃里克
Just go. Stop Erik.
埃里克
Erik.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
埃里克
Erik.
你是罗根  他是汉克·麦考伊
You are Logan. That's Hank McCoy.
我是查尔斯·泽维尔
I'm Charles Xavier.
我们这几天一直在一起
You spent the last couple of days with us.
你嗑药了吗
You're on Acid?
有人给你下药了
Somebody gave you really bad acid.
是吗
Yeah?
再坚持一下  我们会撑过去的
Just hold on tight, we'll get through this together.
天哪  凯蒂
Oh, God! Kitty.
她伤得很重
She is wounded pretty bad.
我控制住他了
I got him.
教授
Professor.
你刚才怎么了
What happened to you?
我看见了一个未来将会折磨我的人
I just saw someone who's going to bring me a lot of pain someday.
瑞雯呢
Where is Raven?
跑了
Gone.
-什么  -我们得走了
- What? - We have to get out of here.
昨天  一些不明攻击者的出现
Yesterday the Paris Peace Summit was
扰乱了巴黎和平峰会
rocked by the appearance of unidentified assailants.
人们此前从未见过这样的人
The likes of which the world has never seen.
巨大的恐慌席卷了全国  人们都在问
Mass hysteria has gripped the nation as people ask,
他们从哪儿来  他们还会回来吗
"Where did they come from? Will they'd be back?",
还有最重要的一点
and most importantly,
他们是敌是友
"Are they friend or foe?".
以上是本节目通讯记者汤米·艾略特
That was "One" correspondent Tommy Elliot
从昨日巴黎和平峰会现场发回的报道
earlier reporting from the Paris Peace Summit yesterday.
谁能告诉我这是怎么回事
What the hell are we dealing with here?
把录音关了
Off the record.
两天前
Two days ago,
这个人  埃里克·兰谢尔
this man Erik Lehnsherr
从五角大楼最高警戒牢房逃出来了
escaped from a maximum security prison inside the Pentagon.
这个女人  曾经是他的同伙
We believe that this woman is a former associate of Lehnsherr's.
62年导弹危机的时候  他们都在古巴
They were together in Cuba the day of the crisis in 1962.
他还和肯尼迪被刺一案有关
He was also implicated in Kennedy's assassination.
那东西又是什么
What about that thing?
目前还不了解  先生
We do not know what that thing is, Sir.
事实上我们对他们全都不了解
Actually we really don't know what any of them are.
不
Yes.
不  我们了解
Yes, We do.
他们是变种人
They are mutants.
这个人能够操控金属
He has the power to control metal.
据我所知你们所有的武器都是金属的
Last I checked that's what most of your weapons were made of.
而她能够变成任何人
And she can transform into anyone.
一名将军
A general.
一名特工
A secret service man.
甚至是您  总统阁下
Even you, Mr. President.
她甚至能走进这间办公室下令发射核武器
She can walk into this office, and order a nuclear strike,
只要她愿意
if she was in the mood.
而这还只是他们中的两个
And that's only two of them.
我们有什么对策或者防御措施吗
Well, do we have any countermeasures, any defense?
我等的就是这个问题
I was waiting for you to ask me that question.
这个项目还处在实验阶段
That's an experimental program, Sir.
严格说来是不合规定的
Strictly, off the books.
你是说世界上有这些变种人
You're telling me these mutants are out in the world,
而我们最佳的防御方式是这些大机器人吗
and our best defense are these giant metal robots?
有很多变种人看起来跟我们一样
Many of the mutants looks like us.
我的哨兵能分辨出他们
My sentinels can tell the difference.
我现在有八台原型机随时可用
I have 8 prototypes ready to go,
他们都是用太空材料制成的
they're built out of a space age polymer,
完全不含金属
not an ounce of metal on them.
我要做一次展示
I wanna make a demonstration,
我要让世界知道我们能保护他们
I want the world to know that we can protect them.
你要怎么启动他们
What do you need to get these things operational?
我已经将激活码交给国会了
I already gave that number to congress
很不幸这个提议被否决了
unfortunately they elected to shut me down.
想要启动可能代价会稍微大一点
It's going to cost a bit more to turn them on.
随你所需
Whatever you need.
另外  如果成功抓住了他们
Oh, and one more thing, if we do manage to capture them,
我希望能用她来做研究
I would like her for research purposes of course.
太可怕了
Terrible thing.
怎么了
What is it?
天生那副模样
Being born like that.
是吗
Is it?
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
每天对着镜子看到那样一张脸
Looking in the mirror and seeing that staring back at you?
我能想象
Yes, I can.
你觉得她是从哪里来的
Where do you think she comes from?
她有家吗
You think she has a family?
是的  她有
Yes, she does.
敢动一颗螺丝钉我就把它插进你喉咙
If I see so much as a screw move I'll jam this into your throat.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
你把我教得很好
You taught me well.
我们很久没这么亲近了
It's been a long time since we were this close.
我很想你
I missed you.
你想杀我
You tried to kill me.
这样其他人才能活
So the rest of us could live.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我收到一条来自未来的消息
I received a message from the future.
少骗我
Don't lie to me.
我从来没有  也永远不会骗你
I never have, I never will.
人类用你的血和基因
Humans use your blood, your genes,
制造出了能毁灭我们的武器
your genes to create a weapon that wipes us all out.
我只是做了我觉得能保护我们未来的事
I was only doing what I thought necessary to secure our future.
那有什么能阻止我
So what's to stop me from
现在杀了你来保护我自己的未来
killing you right now and securing my future?
没有
Nothing.
已经无所谓了
It doesn't matter anymore.
他们得到了你的DNA
They have your DNA,
你的血滴在了街上
your blood was on the street.
那是谁的错
Whose fault is that?
我的
Mine.
我看过他们的计划
I've seen their plans.
他们在制造一种武器
They are creating a weapon,
现在他们已经得到了进行下去的关键东西
and now they have what they need to take it further.
我们必须行动起来
We have to strike now,
趁我们还有优势
while we still hold the upper hand.
我看到了太多同伴的死亡  埃里克
I've seen too many friends die, Erik.
我不想要战争
I don't want a war.
我只想找到杀了他们的人
I only want the man who murdered them.
这就是战争
This is a war.
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
我离开这段时间  你迷失了方向吗
Did you lose your way when I was gone?
你还是查尔斯的瑞雯吗
Are you still Charles's Raven?
还是魔形女
Or are you Mystique?
特拉斯克才是敌人
Trask is the enemy.
杀掉一个人远远不够
Killing one man isn't enough.
对你来说永远都不够
It never was for you.
再见  埃里克
Good Bye, Erik.
怎么了
What happened?
他能走吗
Can he walk?
他需要接受治疗
He need his treatment.
汉克  我能听到他们说话
Hank, I can hear them.
没事的  我能让它停下  我去拿药
It's ok, I'll make it stop. I'll get it.
喂  喂  坚持住
Hey, Hey. Pull yourself together
还没完呢
It's not over yet.
你根本不相信
You don't believe that?
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
这里不能动
As these go,
这里就回来了
this comes back.
他们全都回来了
They all come back.
听着
Look, you know.
我还在这里
I'm still here.
她还在外面
She's still out there.
可我们需要你的帮助  查尔斯
But we need your help, Charles.
不是这样  我需要的是你
Not like this, I need you.
没有你的能力
We can't find Raven..
我们找不到瑞雯
not without your powers.
我多加了一点  因为你少打了一针
I added a little extra cause you missed a dose.
查尔斯
Charles.
汉克  帮我个忙
Hank, do me a favour.
扶我去书房好吗
Would you help me to my study please?
我来帮你
Alright, I get you.
你确定要这么做吗
Are you sure about this?
不确定
Absolutely not.
这种生物真是太神奇了
This creature is extraordinary.
她的基因也许承载了变种的关键
Her genes could hold the key to mutation itself.
我需要更多
I need more.
他们从巴黎街上刮下来的只有这么多了
That's all they were able to scrape off the pavement in Paris.
除了血以外的
More than blood.
我需要脑组织
I need brain tissue.
脊髓液
Spinal fluid.
骨髓
Bone marrow.
想象一下  能变形并根据目标改变的哨兵
Imagine sentinels that could transform, adapt to any target.
只要我能抓住她
If I just get my hands on her.
这个女孩能够大幅加快项目进程
This girl could leap the program forward years,
甚至能加快数十年
decades into the future.
你儿子多大了  少校
How old is your son now, Major?
杰森吗
Jason?
他都快十岁了  不可思议吧
He's coming up on 10 now if you can believe it.
还有八年就要入伍了
Eight years from fighting age.
又有多少我们的儿子和弟兄
And how many of our sons and brothers
被装进尸袋送回家
did we just ship home in body bags?
五万  五万五
Maybe 50? 55000?
而我们的对手呢
How many more on the other side?
从未有过
Never before,
在人类的历史上
in all of human history,
从未有过什么能让全人类都团结起来
has there been a cause which could unite us as a species.
现在有了
Until now.
您非常憎恶变种人吧  博士
You really hate mutants doctor, don't you?
恰恰相反  我因他们的能力而敬佩他们
On the contrary, I rather admire them the things they can do.
我觉得变种人是我们的救星
I assume mutants as our salvation.
也是共同的敌人
And common enemy.
这是我们共同的斗争  为了战胜最终的敌人
Common struggle against the ultimate enemy..
灭绝
Extinction.
我相信我们的新朋友们
I believe our new friends
将帮助我们进入一个新的时代  比尔
are going to help us usher in a new era, Bill.
拥有真实而持久的和平的新时代
A new era of genuine and long lasting peace.
请注意  请注意
Attention! Attention!
两小时后货物将离开
Transport departure in two hours.
重复一遍
Repeat.
两小时后货物将离开
Transport departure begins in two hours.
你上次下来是什么时候
When was the last time you down here?
-我们上次来找学生的时候  -很久了
- Last time we went looking for students. - A life time ago.
欢迎  教授
Welcome, Professor.
瑞雯受伤了  她动作不会太快
Raven is wounded, she won't be moving fast.
我很久没伸展过这些肌肉了
These are muscles I haven't stretched in a long time.
天啊
Gosh!
查尔斯
Charles!
查尔斯  没事了
Charles, It's alright.
我去检查发电机
I'll go check the generator.
跟机器无关  对吧
It's not the machinery, Is it?
-我做不到  我的思想  -你可以的
- I can't do this, my mind... - Yes you can.
-它不听话  -就是有点生锈了
- It won't take it. - It's just a little rusty.
你不懂  这跟生锈没有关系
You do not understand, It's not a question of being rusty.
我可以按下开关  可以转动把手
I can flip the switches, I can turn the knobs.
可是我的力量来自这里  来自...
But my power comes from here, comes from ..
现在它被毁了
And it's broken.
我感觉像自己的某个学生
I feel like one of my students.
无助
Helpless.
下来这里就是个错误
It was a mistake coming down here.
把埃里克弄出来就是个错误
It was a mistake freeing, Erik.
这整个事情就是个严重的错误
This whole thing has been one bloody mistake.
抱歉  罗根  但他们就不该派你回来
I'm sorry, Logan, they sent back the wrong man.
你说得对
You're right.
不该是我
I am.
其实本该是你自己来的
Actually it was supposed to be you.
可我是唯一能撑得过传送的人
But I was the only one who could physically make the trip.
我不知道我们还有多长时间
And I don't know how long we've got here.
但我知道很久以后
But I do know that a long time actually,
从现在起很久以后
a long time from now.
我曾是你彷徨无助的学生
I was your lost helpless student.
是你打开了我的思想
and you unlocked my mind.
你让我认清了自己
You showed me what I was, you showed me what I could be.
我不知道要怎么帮你
I don't know how to do that for you,
没错  我不知道
you're right, I don't.
但我知道有个人也许能做到
But I know someone who might.
读我的记忆
Look into my mind.
你看到我让脑波增幅器成了什么样
You saw what I did to Cerebro.
你不会想让我进入你脑子里的
You don't want me inside your head.
没什么破坏是我没经历过的  相信我
There's no damage you can do that has already been done, trust me.
-罗根  -琴
- Hey, Logan. - Hey, Jean.
-杀了我  -我爱你
- Kill me. - I love you.
你是个...
You're a...
可怜的人
poor man.
别管我的部分
Look past me.
我不想看你的痛苦  我不想看你的未来
I don't want your suffering! I don't want your future!
别管我的未来
Pass my future.
找找你的未来
Look for your future.
就是这样
That's it.
查尔斯
Charles.
这就是我们以后的样子吗
So this is what become of us?
埃里克说得没错
Erik was right.
是人类把我们害成了这样
Humanity does this to us.
除非我们正确地引导他们
Not if we show them a better path.
你到现在还相信
You still believe?
仅仅因为有人跌倒迷了路
Just because someone stumbles, loses their way,
并不意味着他们会永远迷失
it doesn't mean they're lost forever.
有时我们都需要一点帮助
Sometimes we all need a little help.
我不再是以前的我了
I'm not the man I was.
我使用了能力
I opened my mind,
却几乎被压垮
it almost overwhelms me.
你在害怕
You're afraid.
脑波增幅器能感觉到
and Cerebro knows it.
那些声音
All those voices...
那么多的痛苦
So... much... pain.
你怕的不是他们的痛苦
It's not their pain you're afraid of.
是你自己的  查尔斯
It's yours, Charles.
这痛苦虽然可怕
And as frightening as it may be,
却也能使你更加强壮
that pain will make you stronger.
如果你能允许自己去感觉它
If you allow yourself to feel it,
接受它
embrace it.
它就能让你强大得超乎想象
It will make you more powerful than you ever imagined.
这是我们最伟大的天赋
It's the greatest gift we have,
能承受痛苦而不被压垮
to bear their pain without breaking.
这是人性的极致体现
And it's born from the most human power,
希望
hope.
拜托了
Please,
查尔斯
Charles,
我们需要你重拾希望
we need you to hope again.
找到你要的了吗
Find what you were looking for?
供电恢复了
Power is back on.
是的
Yes.
是恢复了
Yes it is.
她失血太多了
She's lost too much blood.
她不能再这么下去了
She can't keep going like this.
我们别无选择  波比
We have no choice, Bobby.
我们可以唤醒他
We can wake him up.
不
No.
他们需要更多时间
They need more time.
我看到了过去
I had a glimpse into the past,
如果我们现在唤醒罗根情况可能会更糟
if we wake Logan now we may set off an even darker course.
他们需要更多时间
They need more time.
瑞雯  停下
Raven, stop.
别跑了
Stop running.
查尔斯
Charles.
你在哪
Where are you?
在家里
Back at the house.
你也该回来
Where you should be.
我需要你回来
I need you to come home.
我知道自己该做什么
I know what I need to do.
如果你杀了特拉斯克
If you kill Trask,
会有更多像他一样的人出现
You will be creating countless more just like him.
那我就把他们也杀了
Then I'll kill them too.
那是埃里克的想法  不是你的
Those are Erik's words, not yours.
跟我一同长大的女孩不会杀戮
The girl I grew up with wasn't capable of killing,
她很善良  公正并充满同情心
she was good, fair, full of compassion.
我有同情心  但不是对特拉斯克
I have compassion, just not for Trask.
他杀了太多我们的同伴
He's murdered too many of us.
阻止她  查尔斯  进入她的大脑
Shut her down Charles, get in her head.
她不让我进去  我快坚持不住了
She's not letting me in I'm barely holding on.
我还不够强大
I'm not strong enough yet.
我知道特拉斯克做了什么
I know what Trask has done.
可杀了他也不能让他们复生
But, killing him will not bring them back.
只会让你陷入万劫不复的境地
It will set you on a path from which there is no return,
我们和他们将陷入无休止的杀戮
an endless cycle of killing us and them,
直到什么都不剩
till there is nothing left.
但我们可以现在就阻止这一切
But we can stop it right now.
你和我
You and I.
只是你必须回家来
You just have to come home.
我必须
I have to.
你真是一点都没变  查尔斯
You haven't changed at all, Charles.
我说了
Like I said.
我知道自己该做什么
I know exactly what I have to do.
她在哪
Where is she?
在机场登机
She's at an airport boarding a plane.
去哪的飞机
Plane to where?
华盛顿特区
Washington DC.
伙计们
Hey guys,
我要给你们看样东西
there is something I need to show to you.
这是我设计的一个系统
It's just a system I designed,
用来收录巴黎事件相关新闻的
to record any news about Paris,
覆盖了全部三家广播网和公共广播公司
over all 3 networks and PBS.
全部三家
All three?
是  还有公共广播公司
Yeah, and PBS.
看看我录到了什么
Look what I found.
明天  美国总统
Tomorrow in front of the White House
将在白宫门口发表声明
the president will make his announcement.
同时出席的还将有国防部长布莱尔
He'll be joined by Secretary of Defense Blair.
以及著名科学家玻利瓦尔·特拉斯克
And has even sought the help of renowned scientist Bolivar Trask.
他将担任总统对抗变种人问题的特别顾问
His special adviser to combat this mutant issue.
白宫将
The White House is....
瑞雯没有意识到  如果她在
Raven doesn't realize but if she kills
这种全球瞩目的情况下杀掉特拉斯克
Trask at an event like that with the whole world watching...
那我这趟就白跑了
Then I came a long way for nothing.
还不止这些  我在一篇报道中看到
And there's more bad news, I saw in a report.
他们在巴黎找到了她的血迹
They found traces of her blood in Paris.
目前看来  他们已经有她的DNA了
For all we know they already have her DNA.
他们只需要这个
Which is all they need.
就能在未来造出哨兵
To create the sentinels in the future.
量子物理学中有个理论称时间是永恒的
Now there's a theory in quantum physics that time is immutable.
时间就像河流  你可以丢个卵石进去
It's like a river, you can throw a pebble and
虽会激起涟漪  但水流总会自我修正
it will create a ripple but the current always corrects itself.
不管你做什么
No matter what you do
始终无法改变水流的方向
the river just keeps flowing in the same direction.
你想说什么
What are you trying to say?
我想说
What I was saying is
万一战争是无可避免的呢
what if the war is inevitable.
万一她注定要杀死特拉斯克呢
What if she's meant to kill Trask.
万一这就是她的本质呢
What if this is just simply who she is.
仅仅因为有人跌倒迷了路
Just because someone stumbles, loses their way,
并不意味着他们会永远迷失
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
我不相信那个理论  汉克
I don't believe that theory, Hank.
我也不相信这就是她的本质
And I can not believe that is who she is.
准备飞机  我们去华盛顿
Ready the plane we're going to Washington.
华   盛   顿   特   区
你还好吧
You alright?
会好起来的
Getting there.
不管今天发生什么
Whatever happens today,
你必须向我保证一件事
I need you to promise me something.
你看过我的记忆  看到了很多不幸
You looked into my mind and you've seen a lot of bad but,
但你也看到了好的回忆
you've seen the good too.
那些X战警
The X-Men.
答应我你会找到我们
Promise me you'll find us.
用你的力量  将我们聚集起来
Use your power, bring us together.
指引我们  领导我们
Guide us. Lead us.
暴风女
Storm,
斯考特
Scott,
琴
Jean.
记住这些名字
Remember those names.
我们有很多人
There's so many of us.
我们会需要你的  教授
We will need you, Professor.
我会尽力的
I will do my best.
你尽力就够了
Your best is enough.
相信我
Trust me.
有12辆运输器过来了  还有16公里
12 carriers inbound, 10 miles.
他们找到我们了
They found us.
今天  成千上万的民众将聚集在这里
Thousands of people will be gathered here today,
他们从世界各地赶来见证这一历史时刻
they come from all over the world to witness history
同时还有来自至少50个国家的记者们
along with news crews from at least 50 different countries.
谢谢
Thank you.
能看看你们的邀请函吗
Can I see your invitations please?
当然可以
Yes, you may.
他们俩是和我一起的
These two are with me.
-请  -谢谢
- Go ahead. - Thank you.
罗根
Logan.
请这边走  先生
Please, this way, sir.
我还没找到她  但她肯定在
I haven't found her yet but she has to be here.
有请美国总统
President of the United States.
我的美国同胞们
My fellow Americans,
今天我们面临着历史上最大的威胁
today we face the greatest threat in our history.
变种人
Mutants.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我们做好了应对这一威胁的准备
We have prepared for this threat.
引用罗伯特·奥本海默的不朽名言
In the immortal words of Robert Oppenheimer.
请看
Behold.
世界将从此不同了
The world will never be the same again.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
你管不了的
No, you can't.
他们来了
Here they come.
兄弟姐妹们  这是为了你们
This is for you, brothers and sisters.
瑞雯
Raven.
我找到她了
I have her.
放开我  查尔斯
Let me go, Charles.
在那  看见了吗
There. You see?
舞台左边那个特勤人员
Secret service man, left to the stage.
-看见了  -快去
- Got it. - Go.
你他妈干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我没叫你启动它们
I didn't tell you to activate it.
我没启动
I didn't.
瑞雯  请听我说
Raven, please listen to me.
我们现在有第二次机会来定义自己
We've been given a second chance to define who we are.
别这么做
Don't do this.
先生们  你们不能过去
Gentlemen, you cannot pass this point.
我们阻止不了这么多
We can't stop that many.
是不能
No.
但我们可以拖延它们
But, we can slow them down.
埃里克
Erik!
快点  快走
Move it ! Come on let's go!!
暴风女
Storm!
进入三级戒备状态
Take us to Def-con 3.
总统先生  我们现在是红色警报
Mr. President we are code red.
空中防御就绪
Air defense ready now.
刚才到底怎么回事
What the hell happened out there?
我会解决的
I'll fix it.
你以前就这么说过
You said that before,
我本要发表声明的
I wanted to make a statement.
现在整个世界都知道我们无法保护他们了
Now the whole goddamn world knows we can't protect them.
我会解决的
I will fix it.
你最好能解决
You damn well better.
查尔斯
Charles!
大家都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
暴风女
Storm!
小心身后
Behind you.
送我过去
Now.
我也许不该问这种事
I'm probably not supposed to ask this kind of a thing.
但在未来  我活下来了吗
But in the future, do I make it?
没有
No.
但我们可以改变未来  对吧
But we can change that, right?
去完成你的使命吧
Do what you were made for.
变种人
你在哪
Where are you?
这里交给我  你去吧
I got this. Go.
天啊  不
Oh dear God, no.
你作为幸存者的日子到此为止了
So much for being a survivor.
这里有个变种人
One of them is in here.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
别杀它
Don't kill it.
我要活的
I need it alive.
这他妈到底怎么回事
What the hell has happened?
你们造了这些武器来消灭我们
You built these weapons to destroy us.
为什么
Why?
因为你们害怕我们的天赋
Because you're afraid of our gifts.
因为我们与你们不同
Because we are different.
人类总是惧怕异类
Humanity has always feared that which is different.
但我现在要告诉你们  告诉世界
But I'm here to tell you, tell the world.
你们应该怕我们
You're right to fear us.
我们才是未来
We are the future.
我们将会继承这片土地
We are the ones who will inherit this earth.
任何试图阻止我们的人
And anyone who stands in our way,
都将遭遇你们面前这些人的下场
will suffer the same fate as these men you see before you.
今天本是你们要展现能力的日子
Today was meant to be a display of your power.
但我现在给你们看看
Instead I give you a glimpse
我的种族可以给你们带来的毁灭
of the devastation my race can unleash upon yours.
就算是对世界的警告吧
Let this be a warning to the world.
而对我的变种人兄弟姐妹们
And to my mutant brothers and sisters out there,
我要说
I say this:
别再躲藏了
no more hiding.
别再受苦了
No more suffering.
你们已在羞辱和恐惧的阴影下生活太久了
You've lived in a shadows in shame and fear too long.
走出来吧
Come out.
加入我的行列  为我们变种人而战
Join me, fight together in the brotherhood of our kind.
新的明天
A new tomorrow
始于今日
that starts today.
我们浪费了这么多年彼此对抗  查尔斯
All those years wasted fighting each other, Charles
只为了那些许珍贵的岁月
to have a precious few of them back.
总统先生
Mr. President.
退后  我说了  退后
Stand down ! I said stand down!
你想表明态度吗
You want to make a statement?
杀了我  没问题
Kill me...fine.
但把其他人放了
But spare everyone else!
真是英雄之举啊  总统先生
Very heroic, Mr. President.
但你却从未打算放过我们的人
But you had no intention of sparing any of us.
我们种族的未来就从现在开始
The future of our species begins now.
变种人
你以前的枪法可更准
You used to be a better shot.
相信我  现在依旧很准
Trust me, I still I'm.
滚出我的思想  查尔斯
Get out of my head, Charles!
瑞雯
Raven,
别让变种人在今天成为世界的敌人
please do not make us the enemy today.
你看看四周  我们已经是了
Look around you, we already are.
不全是
Not all of us.
你目前为止所做的
All you've done so far
只是在救这些人的命
is save the lives of these men.
你可以引导他们
You can show them a better path.
把她弄昏  查尔斯
Shut her down, Charles.
从我们认识起  我就一直在试图控制你
I've been trying to control you ever since the day we met.
看看现在的结果
And look what that's got us.
接下来要发生的一切
Everything that happens now,
都由你来决定
is in your hand.
我相信你  瑞雯
I have faith in you, Raven.
我把他交给你了  查尔斯
He's all yours, Charles.
你把我交给他们  我就死定了
If you let them have me I'm as good as dead.
你知道的
You know that.
我知道
I know.
再见了  老朋友
Good-bye, old friend.
再见  埃里克
Good-bye, Erik.
你确定要让他们走吗
You sure you should let them go?
是的
Yes.
我对他们存有希望
I have hope for them.
未来有一天  汉克
It's going to be a time, Hank.
我们都会重聚
When we're all together.
那罗根呢
What about Logan?
早上好  罗根  你起晚了
Good morning, Logan. Late start.
好好享受午餐吧  干得好
Have a good lunch time. Good job.
-谢谢  -干得很漂亮
- Thank you. - Very good job.
暴风女
Storm.
琴
Jean.
罗根
Hi, Logan.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你在这
You're here.
不然我还能在哪
Where else would I be?
悠着点  伙计
Easy, pal.
有些事怎么就变不了呢
Some things never change.
很高兴见到你  斯考特
Good to see you, Scott.
回头见  琴
See you later, Jean.
教授
Professor.
罗根
Logan.
一切都还好吧
Is everything alright?
好
Yeah.
挺好的
Yeah, I think it is.
你做到了
You did it.
做到什么
Did what?
罗根  你不是要教课吗
Logan, don't you have a class to teach?
教课
A class?
-我来教课  -是啊
- To teach. - Yeah.
历史课
History.
历史
History?
其实我还真需要你帮点忙
Actually, I could use some help with that.
帮什么忙
Help with what?
1973年后的所有历史
Pretty much everything after 1973.
我想我知道的历史跟你有些不同
I think history I know is a little different.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
见到你真高兴  查尔斯
It's good to see you, Charles.
能见到大家真好
It's good to see everyone.
那是
Well,
我要遵守诺言嘛
I had a promise to keep.
咱俩得好好叙叙旧
You and I have lot of catching up to do.
是
Yes.
你记得的最后一件事是什么
What is the last thing you remember?
溺水
Drowning.
过去
The past,
一个崭新和不确定的世界
a new and uncertain world.
变种人拯救了总统和国会
哨兵计划取消
一个充满无限可能
A world of endless possibilities.
和无穷结果的世界
And infinite outcomes.
特拉斯克因出售军事机密被捕
可以吗
Can we?
他还活着
Oh, he is alive!
他在呼吸
He is breathing.
无数的选择决定了我们的命运
Countless choices define our fate.
每个选择  每个时刻
Each choice, each moment,
都是时间长河中的一个涟漪
a ripple in the river of time.
你要我们怎么处置他  史崔克少校
What do you want us to do with him, Major Stryker?
有足够多的涟漪  就能改变潮流
Enough ripples and you change the tide.
把他交给我吧
I'll take him from here.
因为未来永远不会真成定数
For the future is never truly set.